Before starting to make the baseball cap, we first import the background picture
Insert the background picture into the Marvelous Designer 2D window
After that, you can see that its proportion is relatively large
Then we set the size here to 50%
Then confirm
It can be compared that its size is still a little big, so we change it to 30%
Then use the internal line tool to create along the effect on the picture
Then when we create half of it, we can finish this version
After completion, select to open
Then it is to draw other parts of the version
In the process of drawing, press the Ctrl key
Click is to start
To create a red curve point
If you want to create a straight line, just press the left button
Remember to release the Ctrl key
After drawing the baseball cap, we first create the body of the hat
To create the body, we will use the middle shape first
After choosing this shape, create a joint version
Note that it is to create a joint version
When we create a joint version
After creating a joint version
If we modify any of the versions
Other outer frame light green versions that are linked to each other
Will be modified together
After creating a total of six versions
We are going to start to sew the version
You can't use this version at the moment
So let's turn it over first
The method of sewing is very simple
We use the line sewing tool to sew the two sides together
After sewing, we put it in 3D space
Adjust its arrangement
And then open the animation
Then we start to simulate
And then we start to simulate
Because the gravity is off
We can apply a hard drive to all the sheets
And let it hold up
After holding up, we can see
It's like the half of a basketball
That's the basis of the baseball cap we often talk about
In order to prevent it from deforming, we also change its physical attribute to the attribute of Fograin Leather here.
Because this attribute is relatively hard, we can remove the hardening if we connect it.
Direct simulation is also OK.
Then we select all the panels without opening the simulation,
and drag it to the head of the virtual model, and then open the simulation, and let it be covered on the head of the virtual model.
Here, because I used the virtual model prepared before,
we can reduce the surface strength of the virtual model to 0,
making the panel closer to the head.
If you want to modify the head of the hat,
or make it fit the model's head shape,
first of all, we can lengthen the entire panel in the vertical direction.
When we lengthen the entire panel,
the height of the hat as a whole will be increased,
and it will be a little longer.
But it does not widen the entire height of the hat in the head.
If we want to widen it,
we need to select the center of the panel,
double-click to use the center point,
and then widen our selection.
Then we can widen the panel,
or narrow the panel,
so that it fits the head of our virtual model.
Next, we can drag the panel in the state of opening the simulation,
By doing this,
we can quickly double-click the panel to open the simulation.
After that,
you can add the results here.
After the adjustment,
we are going to start making the face.
The eyes of the virtual model
Let's find the two panels of the forehead first.
For other panels,
we can freeze it for the time being.
Then select the middle to open the line, select the symmetry to open the border
In this way, when we modify one side of it, the other side will also be modified at the same time
Because the previous version was re-activated, now we can re-arrange the position of this version
After activation, use the positioning ball tool to adjust it to the position we want to sew
Then we can start to create a sewing line
Then we use the free sewing tool to sew a long section first, then press the Shift key
From the point in front of us to the right side to sew
The length that comes out is the same, we press the Shift key, don't sew it on the side next to the back
Here is the same, sew from right to left, then this side is the same
If you turn to the back of the board, it will still start from this point, from right to left
Just like when we did the dress cat before, it was the same
Here, because the bend strength of the board is relatively large, it will be connected into one
Then we need to use the editing sewing line tool to select all the sewing lines
Set its folding angle at the bottom
Here we set it to 270 degrees, which is an opposite fold angle
But when we set the right angle, we will find that this board can't be turned over no matter what
In fact, it can be compared, as an example, it is a little too wide
So we can adjust the width of this board first
Let it fit the width of the board in front of us
Because I want to use the front of these two boards as a reference
So we can cut points according to the sewing line
After selecting this set of sewing lines with the editing sewing line
There is an increase point at the end of the right key
Because each section is the next starting point
So here you actually choose to be in the ending position or starting position is ok
It will turn into a breakpoint
After forming a breakpoint, we can use this point as a basis to adjust
So from this point on
Use the built-in multi-layer tool to click and draw a split line
After roughly drawing, use the edit board tool to select this line and cut it off
The rest of the parts can be deleted by clicking
After we turn on the simulation, we will find that it is not like before
It will have such a curved effect
Then we can make it a little longer according to the need
Let it be closer to the hat in real life
Or you can change its curve
In order to better reference the effect
We can first reduce the粒子間距 and the conflict thickness of these now activated boards
Let's adjust the curve a bit
Then we also adjust thegeb
Then we can also make the curve a bit rounder
The feature of the double-edged hat is that sometimes we can see the sewing line from the outside.
Here we use the line section to click along this side
You can create a fake sewing line along this side
If you want to modify the type of sewing line, first we can change the name of the window on the side to Top Stitch
Then adjust its properties in the attribute editor below
Regarding the sewing line, first we can choose whether it is a three-dimensional OBJ file or Texture
Then we can change the border
The border is the line between this sewing line to the section we choose
In real life, these hats are supported by a part of the stock price
Then we can also make this effect in the software
Because now the hat is close to the forehead
So we first reverse-activate the virtual model
After finishing the internal structure, put the hat back on the virtual model
After reverse-activation, hide the virtual model
Let's do the internal stock structure first
In order not to affect our simulation speed
First, freeze all the panels that can not be used
Before making the stock price
We usually have a hollow area behind the baseball cap
If we want to make the stock price
We need to dig out this hollow area before making the stock price
So we have to choose these two panels at the back
After canceling the link, set these two panels as symmetrical panels
So that when we dig one side
The other side will automatically be symmetrical
If you want to have a reference
You can use the 3D panel tool in the 3D space
Draw a reference first
First, untangle or activate the two panels at the back
Then we have to choose the 3D panel tool
Click and draw the area we want to dig out
After going to the panel line, double click to end
Then press Shift-A to display all virtual models
When the size is relatively small
Press Ctrl-C to return to the previous step
Re-dig
After the drawing is complete
We can switch to the edit line tool at the top
Select the line you just drew
Right-click to select the internal shape
If there is any need to adjust
We can use the edit panel tool
To directly edit at the 2D window
Reduce the size of the invisible panel
And adjust the size of the UV field
Then adjust the shape of the UV panel
To a 3D plan
There are several ways to edit
Just take advantage of this
And move the UV panel to the right
Click and draw the 2D panel
You can see
There is an overlap
In the left panel
There is an мел
But there is an overlapping
So you can just move it back and forth
And align the line
Just point the 3D panel
And move it to the right
And move these 2 panels
To the right
After that
We can go back and forth
The other versions are all frozen in 3D space, so they won't penetrate the virtual model too much
After we dig the area we need, we can start to build the stock price part in the middle
We can start to build the stock price in the middle, and we can start to build the stock price in the middle
After selecting a side, right-click and select the internal line border
Here we enter a value
This value is the width of the stock we are going to make
The last time this board
Because it is a symmetrical board
So after we create it
There will be automatic symmetry on the other side
This is ok
We will remove the symmetry at the end
And delete the excess internal line
After completion, we can freeze these two boards
Draw the internal line on other boards first
Please press it
Please do not touch the sickle
Next we will extract these stock boards
First of all, we can use the hook and loop tool to extract these small panels
If we use the hook and loop tool, we need to use the hook and loop tool first
Then select all the lines that form the price part
Then press the Enter key to extract the panels
However, if the price that we create later will be attached to the panel at the top or bottom
We have a more convenient way, which is to use the hook and loop tool directly inside
After using the hook and loop tool, the new panels will automatically create the sewing line between the original panels
And they are completely attached in 3D space
It is very convenient for us to make the price
First, let's remove the 3D space
Then cut off the excess panels
In this way, we automatically have a price that fits under the original hat in 3D space
And one side of it automatically forms a sewing line
Then we just need to fill in the remaining sewing lines
Then we can do the same for other panels
This is the way to create a support for the price
If you sometimes hope that you can't see the sewing line of this price on the outer layer
Then we can select all the panels on the outer layer
Then right-click on the outer layer of the column
Just like before
But now we are in the outer layer of the column
There is a circle of panels
There is a sewing line with the original panel
Then we can right-click to remove the 3D space
After removing the 3D space
We can delete the excess internal lines between them
Because if we don't remove the 3D space
When we delete the internal lines on the 3D panel
The internal lines on the inner panel will also be deleted
In this way, there is no place to sew the price inside
Now because there is another panel on the outer layer
In this way, we can't see the sewing line inside
Next, we have to make the inner border of this hat
First, the back piece has two places to be extruded
We have to use the internal line tool first
To draw out the part of the extrusion position
Then the third piece is ended
After drawing, select these two lines and cut the seam allowance
To make sure that the side is rectangular
Select the bottom of the side and draw a horizontal line
To make sure that the side is rectangular, draw a vertical line
In the property editor, we write the length of the 2D line
And then, according to 22mm
We will draw a square with a width of 22 mm
After drawing, we will start to create the sewing line
After creating the square
Put it apart from other panels in the 2D window
So it won't block other panels
Then use the sewing tool to do sewing
When sewing, be careful because the edges are all inside the inner layer of the board.
So we must separate the position of the inner and outer layers of the board,
then sew the bottom of the board and the bottom of the inner board together.
After using the sewing tool, click on the longest edge of the board first,
then press the Shift key and skip the button in the middle.
Then click from left to right once.
After reaching the last edge, jump back to the bottom of the board on the left.
The mouse is also pressed towards the left.
When sewing, be sure to pay attention to the direction.
After choosing this side board, right-click and select Add to Inside.
The sideboard will automatically stick to the inside of the hat.
At this time, if you start the simulation,
it will automatically turn over,
so we need to make a setting for its folding angle.
Here, because there is a block of the board,
it is not very convenient to use the folding arrangement tool.
So we can add it directly to the inside first,
then use the editor sewing tool to adjust the folding angle between the sewing lines.
Then we need to fix it on the side,
so we first use the built-in multi-sided tool
to draw two inner lines here.
After drawing, we can choose the sewing line tool in the 3D window
and sew these two sides together.
Now that the side is ready,
we can start using the editor sewing tool to set the folding angle.
The fold angle should be set to 0.
Since they are now on the back,
that is, both sides are facing out,
so its angle should be set to 0.
In order to prevent some instability in the follow-up,
we first reduce the particle diameter of this small sideboard to 5,
and the conflict thickness to 1.
Then we can take the top part of this sideboard to come out,
and then we can fix it right here.
After the creation is done here,
we will begin to do the fold-out part behind the cap.
First, the middle line is a little crooked,
so let's adjust the position of this line in the middle.
Thank you.
Next, we also adjust it to the horizontal direction, so that it is as square as possible.
Copy a square shape and sew it to the middle position to wait for the belt of the adjustment belt.
Then adjust its width and make a few round corners using the round-shape curve tool.
After those twoquis, use the internal 140-Φ curve function to create a second one between them to color smeared plaid felt forcing the inside.
After those two
then choose these two edges and use the internal 140-Φ curve function to create a second one between them to color smeared plaid felt forcing the inside.
Here you can see we have'd already added fibers to these raison dance satin flatOOOOOOOOOO了
Xiou
Then we create a sewing line to sew them together.
In Marvelous Designer, if we want to make a buckle effect,
we have two ways to choose.
Here I use the method of adding and subtracting,
so we need to create two internal lines first,
and a slightly arched board with fabric in the middle.
After creating this rectangular board that is equal to them,
we sew it on the two sides of the internal line just created.
After sewing it together on both sides,
we can make a arrangement for the board.
Then we need to reduce the particle diameter of this small board,
and reduce the conflict thickness.
The reduction of the particle diameter
is to make it equal to them,
so that it will have a more obvious effect when it is arched.
Here, no matter how we adjust this board,
it still does not arch.
The reason is that the bending strength of our board is particularly high.
When the bending strength is particularly high,
it is like a steel body,
and it is not easy to bend.
So it's like we usually make those steel sticks,
and when the bending strength is particularly high,
you can't bend it.
Once we have reduced the value of the three bending strength,
we can see that the board is arched.
Next,
we will gradually shorten its width,
so that it forms a slightly arched effect.
Then we open the library window,
and find the buckle or ring in the hardware and trims.
After finding the buckle,
we can use the double-click to insert this component,
and then click on this glue tool
to stick it on the top of our board.
After sticking it,
pay attention to its direction, right?
Then we can click on the release button on the upper right
to release the proportion of this buckle.
Then,
use the positioning ball to drag it to the appropriate position.
This position will then support the upper board on the upper board.
Next,
we will press the push button on the top of our board,
and then click on the button to Treble,
then click on its direction.
Then,
we will have a button to push the button to the right,
so that we can press stick to this button.
After that,
we will press shift A to call the virtual model.
Then,
Then don't copy directly, because if you copy directly, our virtual model is back to life.
The current version can't fit the original head shape very well, so we need to put the hat on the virtual model's head again.
Press Ctrl-A to select all the panels and drag them upwards to move the hat away from the head a little bit.
If it's not stable, select all the panels and drag them up a little bit.
Finally, we can see that while the virtual model is stable, we can adjust its position slowly.
After adjustment, freeze all the panels.
We will activate it separately.
We will adjust the front and back panels of the virtual model.
First of all, the face-up panel is now tilted upwards.
Next, we can use the editor's line tool to select the line in the middle and adjust its fold angle.
Reduce the fold angle a little bit to make it a downward extension effect.
On the other hand, if you want it to be tilted up,
you can adjust the fold angle a little bit.
We can adjust the fold angle to be a little bit bigger.
Now let's move on to the virtual model.
But be careful.
The reason why we have the hair here is because our hats are facing this way.
When you make it, you must pay attention to this.
Next, select the inner line and the end line here to create the position of the seam line.
to create the position of the seam line
Then create a cologne layer
so that the seam line between the outer layer and the inner layer will automatically create
and their patterns are the same
If you want to adjust the decoration of the top of the head
we can go to the menu bar of the button
to select its type
and make a change to the type of this button
Now switch to the button here
and then select a type of button at the bottom
Then you can adjust its shape in the attribute editor
Here I change it to a semicircular or flat shape
After adjustment, you can manually use the positioning ball to adjust its position
But don't turn on the simulation
Otherwise it will bounce out again
and it will be like this